Selvasarukesh K

selvasarukesh-portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode Email: sarukesh2637@gmail.com | Mobile: 91 6384066040

Location: Pune, Maharastra, India

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a skilled web developer with over **2.5 years of experience** in **Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PL/SQL**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Angular, and SpringBoot** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Java , HTML, CSS , TypeScript ,PL/SQL

Frameworks : Angular, Spring, SpringBoot

Databases : Oracle, PostgreSQL

Dev Tools : Git, Gitlab, Docker, Power BI, RedHat OpenShift, Jenkins

EXPERIENCE

Senior Executive - Software Development

Jun 2024 - Present

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Pune

- Managed the design, development, and maintenance of payment gateways and mandates .
- Worked on **cloud migration** to enhance user experience.
- Acquired extensive experience managing multiple applications in a dynamic IT environment.

Graduate Trainee - Software Development

Jun 2024 - Jun 2024

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Pune

• Collaborated on the development and enhancement of multiple real-time insurance applications using **Angular**, **Java**, and **Spring Boot** frameworks.

Intern - Software Development

Sep 2022 - Jun 2023

Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance, Coimbatore

 Acquired hands-on experience in IT real-time culture and advanced technologies through a comprehensive internship program.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Application

8.20 GPA

Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya College of Arts and Science - Coimbatore

Jun 2020 - Jun 2023

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)

72.83 GPA

Syed Ammal Metric Hr Sec School - Ramanathapuram

Jun 2019 – May 2020

PROJECTS

Payment Gateway and Mandate

Angular, Spring Boot, Oracle, Javascript, Git

Source Code

- Designed and developed a Optimized website for a seamless **customer experience** and implemented real-time mandates with a clean workflow.
- Ensured seamless and efficient service delivery through **cloud** integration.

BloodSecure Management

Angular, Spring Boot, PostgresSQL, Git

Source Code

• We allow users to register their blood details and for administrators or other users to locate nearby donors in emergency situations.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Java Developer by Coding Ninja
- Certified in Java Spring Framework 6 with Spring Boot 3 Udemy
- Certified Java Developer by Spoken Tutorial